Abhishek Bhattacharjee

abhishekb1@mail.usf.edu | (313) 652-6839 | Tampa, FL | linkedin.com/in/abhishekbhattacharjee11 | github.com/abhi11

SUMMARY

Pursuing MS in Computer Science at University of South Florida. More than three years of experience in software development. Fluent in Go, Java, and Python, various SQL and NoSQL databases, and have extensive knowledge of the AWS ecosystem. Find more on my website (http://abhishekbhattacharjee.me/about/).

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science (Thesis), University of South Florida, Tampa, FL

Expected May 2019

GPA: 3.7

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology, University of Pune, Pune, India

Aug 2010 - May 2014

GPA: 3.7 (First Class with Distinction)

SKILLS

Programming: Go, Java, Python, Bash, and C

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cassandra, DynamoDB, MongoDB, Redis, TitanDB, ElasticSearch, Prometheus

IDE: Emacs, Eclipse, IntelliJ, Atom, GoLand
OS: GNU/Linux(Debian derivatives), Mac OS X

Version Control: Git, Perforce

Message Queues: Kafka, RabbitMQ, AWS SQS, Redis Pub-Sub

Other Tools: Storm, Docker, AWS services, Heroku, JUnit, TestNG, Ansible

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL

Oct 2017 - Present

- I look at various dynamics of social networks represented as graphs, and try to predict various events like growth of the graph, link formations etc.
- Working on a project by DARPA, where the objective is to simulate the dynamics of GitHub
- Using, Python and libraries like Pandas extensively, also using ElasticSearch for indexing huge datasets.

Software Development Engineering Intern, Veritas Technologies LLC, Mountain View, CA

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Developed a load balancer for Docker containers inside Flex Appliance using Go, Prometheus, and BoltDB
- Designed the entire REST based microservice architecture from scratch, the project was immensely appreciated and was adopted as a feature for the next release of Flex Appliance

Application Engineer, Media.Net(Directl), Pune, India

Jul 2016 - Jul 2017

- Implemented a proxy server for OpenRTB requests in Go, owned various backend services for the mobile ad-tech team.
- Developed an event sourcing framework for storing ad-impressions using Go, Kafka, and Cassandra.
- Implemented the backend for an Android application scrapper, using TitanDB and Play framework for REST endpoints

Web Craftsman (Backend), Betacraft, Pune, IN

Dec 2015 - Jun 2016

- Worked as a **Go** developer, writing various backend services from scratch. Designed and developed the entire backend of *AppSurfer* using **Go**. Took design decisions regarding the databases, message queues, and also handled DevOps
- Designed and implemented many client projects independently. Used various AWS technologies like EC2, S3, SQS, RDS,
 CloudSearch, ElasticBeanstalk, CodeDeploy, Auto-Scaling, and Route53

Associate Software Engineer, Veritas Technologies LLC, Pune, IN

Jun 2014 - Dec 2015

- Started here after my undergrad studies. Developed key features in *Veritas Resiliency Platform* like Migrate, Takeover, Fire-drill for VMWare ESX and Microsoft Hyper-V based virtual environments
- Implemented various kinds of risk detections for the above environments. Implemented these features entirely in Java.
 Also, helped the build team in building the CI framework based on Maven

Participating Student, Google Summer Of Code '14, Debian

Jan 2014 - June 2014

- Contributed Open Source Software for Debian, the prominent GNU/Linux distribution. Implemented metadata extractor for Debian packages (.deb) in conformation with AppStream specifications to be used in Software Center like applications
- The extractor was written in **Python** and **SQLAlchemy** was used for the database ORM. Attended *DebConf*, annual Debian conference after successfully completing the project.